The Samuel Gardner Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Correspondence, Series II
  - To Gardner and others regarding Harmonic Thinking, II.A
    - Dykema, Peter W., April 2, 1941; typed letter signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Erskine, John, October 18, 1939; typed letter signed xc (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Flesch, Carl, December 9, 1939; typed letter signed xc (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Findlay, Francis, October 23, 1939; March 19, 1940; typed letters signed xc (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Fischer, Walter (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Fort Worth Conservatory of Music. (Box 6, Folder 1)
      See Whitlock, E. Clyde
    - Franklin Washburn Violin Studios. (Box 6, Folder 1)
      See Washburn, Franklin
    - Golty, Eric V. de (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Grand Rapids Public Schools. (Box 6, Folder 1)
      See Armstrong, Donald D.
    - Hartmann, Arthur, October 24, 1939; typed letter signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Heifetz, Jascha, November 3, 1958; typed letter signed xc (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Indiana University (Box 6, Folder 1)
      See Sanders, Robert L.
    - Lesinsky, Adam P., December 11, 1939; November 25, 1940; typed letters signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Mannes, David, October 4, 1939; typed letter signed xc (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Mannes School of Music. (Box 6, Folder 1)
      See Mannes, David
    - Marywood College. Department of Music. (Box 6, Folder 1)
      See Walter, Sister Maria
    - Mason, Daniel Gregory, July 30, 1939; typed letter signed xc (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Mursell, James L., March 19, 1941; typed letter signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - National School Music Competition Festivals. (Box 6, Folder 1)
      See Lesinsky, Adam P.
    - New England Conservatory of Music. (Box 6, Folder 1)
      See Findlay,.Francis
    - Perlman, George, September, 1939; November, 1939; typed letters signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Pittsburgh Musical Institute. (Box 6, Folder 1)
      See Yost, Gaylord
    - Polah, Andre, May 29, 1940; typed letter signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Queens College. (Box 6, Folder 1)
      See Stringham, Edwin J.
    - Sanders, Robert L., October 15, 1941; typed letter signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Smith, David Stanley, February 23, 1940; typed letter signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Spalding. Albert, November 6; autograph letter signed xc (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Spurbeck, Samuel W., June 25, 1940; typed letter signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - State Normal School, Potsdam, NY. Crane Department of Music (Box 6, Folder 1)
      See Spurbeck, Samuel W.
    - Stringham, Edwin J., September 9, 1939; typed letter signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Swalin, Ben, December 12, 1939; typed letter signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Syracuse Symphony Orchestra. (Box 6, Folder 1)
      See Polah, Andre
    - Syracuse University. (Box 6, Folder 1)
      See Butler, Harold L.
    - Tuthill, Ruth Wood, October 26, 1939; typed letter signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - University of North Carolina. Department of Music. (Box 6, Folder 1)
      See Swalin, Ben
    - University of North Carolina. Women's College. (Box 6, Folder 1)
      See Altvater, H. Hugh
    - Van Hoesen, Karl D., October 13, 1939; typed letter signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Walter, Sister Maria, 1939; typed letter signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Washburn, Franklin, September 8, 1938; typed letter signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Whitlock, E. Clyde, October 21, 1939; January 20, 1940; typed letters signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Yale School of Music. (Box 6, Folder 1)
      See Smith, David Stanley
    - Yost, Gaylord, October 7, 1939; typed letter signed (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Ysaye, Antoine, July 13; autograph card signed xc (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - General., II.B
    - Letters from Gardner., II.B.1
      - Heifetz, Jascha, January 9, 1969; typed letter signed (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Ozawa, Seiji, September 4, 1979; typed letter signed (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Letters to Gardner., II.B.2
      - Altman, Albert L., August 16, 1946; typed letter (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Altman, Albert L., January 10, 1947; June 21, 1948; typed letters signed (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Boston Pops Orchestra. (Box 6, Folder 2)
        See Williams, John
      - Haertel, Hermann, May 1, 1946; typed letter signed (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Heifetz, Jascha, October 5, 1981; telegram xc (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Kiwanis Concert Orchestra. (Box 6, Folder 2)
        See Haertel, Hermann
      - National Association of Schools of Music. (Box 6, Folder 2)
        See Tuthill, Burnet C.
      - Staten Island Civic Symphony Orchestra. (Box 6, Folder 2)
        See Altman, Albert L.
      - Suzuki, Waltraud, February 7, 1971; October 28, 1972; typed letters signed xc (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Tuthill, Burnet C., April 7, 1941; typed letter signed (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Williams, John, July 16, 1980; typed letter signed (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Programs and Clippings, Series III
  - Programs featuring Gardner as performer, conductor, or composer., 1921-1981; 21 items (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Photocopies of programs and reviews featuring Gardner as performer, conductor, or composer. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper and magazine clippings. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Photocopies of press notices about Gardner. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Publisher's advertisements for Harmonic Thinking and advertisements for recordings of Gardner as performer and composer., 6 items and duplicates (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Biographical Material, Series IV
  - Miscellaneous biographical items (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Including resume, photocopies of biographical entries for Gardner in music reference books, and photocopies of articles about the Kneisel Quartet.
  - Interviews with and articles by Gardner (Box 6, Folder 9)
    All photocopies of magazine articles.
  - Interview with Gardner on June 4, 1975, Typescript (40 p.); 28 cm. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Interview conducted by Kenneth K. Goldstein as part of Columbia University's Thomas A. Edison Project.
- Photographs, Series V
  - Photos of Gardner alone. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    2 items, both autographed "To Yale University, in appreciation. Samuel Gardner."
  - Photos of Gardner and others. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    Kneisel at Blue Hill, Maine, about 1913, with his pupils. (Photocopy)
    Violin classes in Stamford and Greenwich, CT, 1934.
    Gardner as guest at concert given by Toledo public school classes, 1947.
    Gardner conducting Toledo public school classes, 1948.
    Gardner as conductor with Staten Island Civic Symphony Orchestra.